paul90brown+resume@gmail.com +1 (817) 382-9696 paulsprogrammingnotes.com

Qualifications Summary

Full-stack developer specializing in data-driven Python & Javascript web applications.

Github Projects

- heckingoodboys.com (Github)
 - o A regularly updated slideshow with some of the most wonderful dog pictures.

Technical Skills

Python	Javascript	Django	Flask	Vue.js
Docker	MySQL	MongoDB	PostgreSQL	Linux
PHP	SQLAlchemy	jQuery	Bootstrap	Jinja2

Professional Experience

- Senior Software Engineer, Included Health (Doctor On Demand) Remote (July 2020 Present)
 - Worked on the Platform Engineering team to improve infrastructure and shared code to improve reliability of the company's Django telemedicine platform.
 - Helped improve CI build pipeline speed by more than 300%.
 - Helped containerize application and improve deployment speed.
 - o Improved test coverage and migrated large codebase from Python 2.7 to 3.8 and Django 1.11 to 3.2.
 - Improved Mypy (type hinting) implementation and used it to find bugs.
 - Improved application performance by reducing query counts and adding missing database indexes.
 - o Implemented Sentry error monitoring and used it to catch bugs early in the development process.
- Full-Stack Engineer, Bloodbuy.com Dallas, TX

(Jan. 2018 – June 2020)

- o Built well-tested features for a built-from-scratch Django e-commerce marketplace.
- Improved application performance by simplifying database schema and reducing query counts.
- Developed ETL pipeline for getting delivery data from carriers.
- Improved e-mail template browser compatibility with MJML.
- Improved organization security by implementing password manager and improving network security.
- Dockerized application and moved testing from Jenkins to CircleCI.
- Deployed software using Heroku.
- Senior Software Engineer, rewardStyle Dallas, TX

(Mar. 2015 – Jan. 2018)

- o Built RESTful API using Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy for the launch of the LIKEtoKNOW.it mobile app.
- o Improved caching, performance, and scalability of LIKEtoKNOW.it.
- Used Docker to containerize applications.
- Built microservices using the Apache Thrift RPC framework.
- Developed ETL pipelines to upsert 30+ million rows into a MySQL database daily.
- Improved accuracy of customer facing analytics.
- · Assisted with engineer onboarding, code review, and bug fixes to Node.js, PHP, and Python software.
- Deployed software on AWS infrastructure using Ansible.

Engineer I, Ericsson - Plano, TX

- (Aug. 2013 Mar. 2015)
- Won an Ericsson PRIDE Award in the category of Processes & Tools. One of only 29 employees (out of approx. 8,000) to receive this award.
- Used Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy to develop database-driven web applications to provide useful insights from raw data.
- Created Python tools to automate data aggregation, scraping, and report generation.
- o Gathered requirements from engineers and took ideas from prototype to launch.
- Software Development Intern, Ericsson Plano, TX

(Aug. 2012 – Aug. 2013)

- o Built widely used internal web application using a web framework (PHP's Yii).
- o Gained Python experience while creating scripts to automate tasks for network engineers.
- Learned to use Git and resolve merge conflicts as I worked with other developers.
- Created an iOS application using Phonegap.
- Became skilled at creating charts using Javascript charting libraries.
- Provided Sharepoint support to coworkers.

Volunteer Work

Treasurer, Dallas Makerspace

(Feb. 2013 – Dec. 2014)

- Handled bookkeeping with Quickbooks, accounting, reporting, and billing.
- o Served on Board of Directors from May 2013 until May 2014.

Education

Degree	Major	Institution	Graduation Year
Bachelors	Computer Science	Thomas Edison State University	2013